Caleb W. Lovell

821 W River Trail Terrace, Apt. 633, Salt Lake City, UT 84123, USA caleblovell1@gmail.com | +1 (262) 349-5921 | linkedin.com/in/caleblovell | www.caleblovell.dev

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack **web developer** with experience in responsive applications and data visualization. Broad knowledge of major web technologies and passionate about creating effective and user-friendly design. Background in political science and linguistics with a strong understanding of data analysis.

EDUCATION

DevMountain | Lehi, Utah

Feb. 2019 - May 2019

Full-stack Web Development Immersive Bootcamp

Miami University | Oxford, Ohio Bachelor of Arts | Overall GPA 3.57 / 4.00 Sept. 2013 – May 2017

Majors: Strategic Communication & Political Science

PROJECTS

USA County Explorer | Interactive Map Site of US County Data

usacountyexplorer.com

- Site's main view is a map of all US counties with their data and a corresponding shading function that colors the map according to the users' preferences.
- Users can login to access full CRUD ability to add, edit, and delete the counties they want to view later.
- Built using D3.js, React, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, Node.js, PresgreSQL, Redux and API calls.

LyricsLog | Language Learning Site for Song Lyrics

lyricslog.dev

- Site for creating and viewing user submitted translations for song lyrics with the option to add explanations for each line.
- Song view highlights lyrics and explanations dynamically to facilitate learning.
- Built using React, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, Node.js, PresgreSQL, Redux and BCrypt authorization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Translator | Self-Employed – USA, Ecuador, Brazil, Part-Time

June 2017 – Present

- Translated hundreds of safety and technical documents between English and Spanish.
- Investigated unfamiliar technical topics to better understand the information and choose the most accurate phrasing possible.
- Served as a personal interpreter in Ecuador on a clean water humanitarian trip, explaining the technical process of filter installation to locals.

English Teacher | Come Together English School – São Paulo, Brazil, Full-Time

Nov. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Taught students of all ages and English levels as an international guest teacher.
- Organized and led language classes in an immersive environment, making use of a variety of teaching techniques to explain linguistic topics in an understandable manner.

DEV SKILLS & LANGUAGES

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- React / React.js
- Redux / Redux.js
- D3 / D3.js

- Node / Node.js
- PostgreSQL
- Portuguese Fluent
- Spanish Advanced
- Italian Intermediate